Guide to the James A. Tutt Papers, 1807-1908
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
James A. Tutt papers 1807-1908
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Tutt, James A.
4.0 linear feet 1,806 Items
Mercantile clerk and postmaster of Calhoun (Henry Co.), Mo.
Business and personal correspondence and papers (chiefly 1835-1858) of James A. Tutt and various members of the Tutt family relating to Tutt's removal from Virginia to Missouri, the migration of other members of the family to the Old Northwest and to the Trans-Mississippi West, frontier conditions and the difficulties of settling in the West, and Tutt's mercantile activities and career as postmaster of Calhoun, Mo.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The James A. Tutt Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1950.
Biographical Note
Mercantile clerk and postmaster of Calhoun (Henry Co.), Mo.
Collection Overview
Papers of James A. Tutt contain business letters, receipts, promissory notes bills, invoices, and account sheets concerning, in general, the migration of Tutt and his family from Virginia to Missouri. The papers contain comments on the hiring and selling of slaves, land speculation, and action against Mormons accused of enticing Indians to help them take over Jackson County, Missouri. There are also a ledger of Tutt's general store at Millersburg, Callaway County, Missouri, 1843-1844; a ledger kept by Matthew Arbuckle, U.S. postmaster at Calhoun, 1851-1853, showing postage paid for newspaper and periodical subscriptions by local residents; a volume containing accounts, 1873-1877, of the Calhoun Manufacturing Company, producers of wooden parts for buggies; the ledger, 1879-1883, of a sawmill owned by David H. Pigg and D. W. Pigg, with many accounts for laborers; and three incomplete volumes including a general store inventory, 1855, accounts of Tutt's wool carding operation, 1855, and mercantile accounts, 1855-1858.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Tutt family
Frontier and pioneer life -- West (U.S.)
Merchants -- Missouri -- Calhoun
Migration, Internal -- United States
Postal service -- Missouri
Postmasters
Missouri -- Emigration and immigration
Northwest, Old -- Emigration and immigration
West (U.S.) -- Emigration and immigration
Contents of Collection
- James A. Tutt Papers, 1807-1908, (10 boxes, 1 bound volume)
  - Papers, 1802-1842 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1843-1844 (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1845-1846 (Box 3)
  - Papers, 1847-1849 (Box 4)
  - Papers, 1850-1852 (Box 5)
  - Papers, 1853-1854 (Box 6)
  - Papers, 1855-1856 (Box 7)
  - Papers, 1857 (Box 8)
  - Papers, 1858-1908 and undated. (Box 9)
  - Volumes (Box 10)
  - Volume (Volume F:6690)